Friends welcome back to insurance
seva.com I got a little late in this video. I got a little
late because I was
searching and was looking to
bring a topic which is your favorite topic, that's why I got a little
late in this video.
You are going to enjoy today's video a lot, it is going to be
very interesting
because it is your favorite topic, but first of all
I would request you to subscribe to the channel
and click on the bell icon.
[Music] The
importance has been explained to us very well. It is
said that one should
not remember bad times, but one should never forget bad times.
You will
remember very well that day of the second wave of Covid 19, the
time when
even after paying hospital bills worth lakhs of rupees, many people could
not be saved, at that time we actually came to know the importance
of health insurance,
but health insurance policy covers
only in-patient treatment, that is, it covers
hospital expenses
or DK treatment. There are
very few health insurance policies
which cover OPD.  There is a tax, that is,
outpatient tax, and a significant amount of your income
goes into your outpatient treatment every year.
Policies that cover outpatient treatment are
very costly and also
impose a small sub-limit on outpatient treatment. The
health insurance company
charges a premium above that sub-limit. Today, I
bring to you a plan that will
provide you with outpatient treatment benefits, diagnostic
test expenses, and medicine
expenses. The premium is very
economical. Friends, this plan is called
Star Health Outpatient Care Insurance
Policy. Let me tell you a little about Star Health.
Star Health and
Allied Insurance Company is the first
standard loan company in our country.
If we talk about its size, Star Health is the
largest standard loan health insurance
company. Its network is also very large, and
its hospitals
are also available for cashless treatment in India.
So, friends, let's see the benefits of this policy.
This
policy covers your outpatient
consultation expenses, i.e. OPD
expenses. When you consult a doctor, you
pay a consultation fee to the doctor.
That consultation fee can range from ₹1,000 to
₹4,000-4,000, depending on the
type of doctor.
This policy also covers diagnostic
tests. If the doctor prescribes
any diagnostic or lab test in the OPD,
that will also be covered.
If you need any kind of
physiotherapy, that
physiotherapy will also be covered under this policy.
Dental treatment and
ophthalmic treatment will also be covered under this policy. But
both these treatments will be for eye
and eye treatment. Let us
know who can take this policy and
how it can be added to this policy.
This policy can be
availed by a person between 18 years and 50 years of age. A
maximum of six people can be added to this policy.
Both individual and family floater
options will be available in this policy. If we
talk about dependent child, then the
definition of dependent child in this policy is that a child between 31 days and up to 25
years will be considered a dependent
child. Both individual and
family floater options will be
available to you in this policy. It will be for
1 year only. You will
not get 2-year or 3-year options in this policy
because the company has included only 1-year term
in the policy. But
you will get the option of lifelong renouncing, that is, if
you purchase the policies today, then you
can run this policy for lifelong.
Three variants of the plan are given - Silver,
Gold and Platinum. There is
only one difference between Silver, Gold and Platinum. The
thing which differentiates it from
Silver Gold to Platinum is the
waiting period for pre-existing diseases, that is,
if you opt for Silver, then if
you have any other pre-existing disease,
then it will be cured after 1 year if you
opt for Gold.  If there is any Priya existing
disease, then it will be taxed after two years.
If you opt for platinum and there is any
Priya existing disease, then it will be
taxed after one year only. In this policy, there will be
time-barring options. You can avail the option of
OPD of 25000, OPD of 75000 or OPD of ₹1 lakh.
I have told you the difference between Silver, Gold and Platinum. The initial waiting
period will be of 30 days and
you can avail Priya existing disease as per the variants of Silver, Gold and Platinum. If the
premium is less than ₹25000, then you can add this
policy to it and avail its tax
benefit.
So friends, you know
how we will take the claim in this policy, that is,
how will we avail the benefits of this policy, OPD benefit.
Friends, the
OPD benefit that you will avail in Star Outpatient Care Policy,
you can avail it only through Star's network hospital i.e. network facility.
You will have to
go to Star Health's app and
book it online, which means
you will get the facility online only. Also, let me
tell you that the diagnostic tests in this policy, i.e.,
Diagram
Stick, Physiotherapy, and Pharmacy, you will also
book it through Star Health's Star Health app. Friends, in this policy,
you will be given the same discount on medicines,
that is, you can avail a discount of 10 to 15% on
medicines.
Along with this, you will also be given a diagnostic
discount, that is, a
discount of 15 to 30% on diagnostic tests. The
doctor is in their network list, where
you can avail cashless OPD.
Also, an oil consultation facility will be provided in this policy.
Teleconsultation friends
will be unlimited in this policy, which means
you can do any amount of oil concentration in this policy.
Unique facility offered by over
technology, that is,
through Doctor StarUp, you
can avail all these facilities. Friends, let's
talk about clamp procedure.  Because the
most important part of any insurance company
is the claim processor,
in this policy you
can claim both cashless and bankrupt ways,
reimbursement will be given to you only in emergency conditions,
you can make cashless claim anytime, to make cashless available,
first of all you have to download Star Health i.e. Star Power Up
in your mobile, your Android or
your iPhone,
login to this app with your mobile
number or policy number, after that
this app will be available for you to
book OPD consultation, to purchase medicine
or to get left test done, the
latest will be done at your home,
you will have to visit for diagnostic,
but if due to any reason there is an emergency
and you have to claim reimbursement,
then it is best that you
take the policy through an agent, contact the agent, the agent
will help you in completing all the formalities, however, I will
tell you its procedure, there is a claim
form, it has to be filed completely
along with the doctor's  Prescription, Doctor
's payment receipt, Diagnostic test
report (if any), Diagnostic
test bill, you have to attach it with all the claim forms
along with your KYC i.e. Aadhar
card, PAN card, photo and a
cancelled cheque because the
insurance company will deliver the claim amount to you in this account.
Friends, let's talk about the
premium. Let's know how Star Health has decided the
premium in the Star Outpatient policy.
See, in this policy, the
premium has not been kept according to the band, the premium has been kept only according to the term.
They have decided the premium of Rs. 250000 and Rs. 1 lakh.
Here, the premium will remain the same on any front. Let's
talk about an
ideal family size, that is, two adults, two kids, husband,
wife and two children. In our country,
this is an ideal family size. So,
on any front, husband, wife, two children, that is,
per member and the premium for OPD of ₹25000 will be Rs.
8649, that is, Rs. 8600. If you  If we avail ₹1
lakh then the premium is
Mantra 19000 7100.
If we take Gold, that is, if there is any
Priya existing and we want to
reduce the Priya existing waiting period,
then we will have to pay a little more premium.
Instead of 8600, you have to pay 10000 300
and here instead of 19000, you have to
pay 23000 600.
If you
want to reduce your Priya existing waiting period further to
just one year, then there is a little
more additional premium, that is ₹11000
for 25000 and for ₹1 lakh, then it
is 25000, that is, the
compatibility of the lovers has been kept quite economical.
In this policy, permanent exclusions will also be
usual today, which are
listed and prescribed in health insurance policies, the same is almost there
which is
permanently there in all health insurance policies.  There are explored diseases,
friends, OPD is such a component
which everyone has to deal with at some point in their life
and a good amount of our income
goes into OPD every year,
especially for those people who have
small children at home because the
immunity of small children is very weak,
like when the season changes, there is some season
or there is some disease or infection,
most of the children get infected, so a
good amount of our income goes into OPD, so
especially for those customers
who spend a good amount of more than ₹ 10000 in OPD in a year,
then this plan is very beneficial for them, so
how did you like this plan, give your suggestions,
give your comments and tell me
how I can improve my videos
and make them more
informed, along with that I would again
request you to subscribe to the channel
and click on the bell icon,
along with this I
would also like to tell you that the next video which I am
bringing will be  In this video, I am bringing
you a completely different topic and your
favourite topic is mutual funds
[music]